## **Ioannis Papadopoulos**

Washington DC, 20037

Phone: 202 938 6673 | Email: iann2048@gmail.com LinkedIn: <u>YiannisPapadopoulos</u> Portfolio: <u>Link</u>

Versatile graphic and ux/ui designer, passionate about crafting meaningful products based on the design way of thinking. Solid research and learning skills that help adapting in challenges such as working in different environments, print and digital, mobile and desktop, individual or collaborative. Highly motivated in communicating and sharing skills and knowledge with colleagues or people that want to get into the design field.

#### **Skills**

**Technical:** Photoshop / Illustrator / After Effects / InDesign / Miro / Invision / Figma / Bootstrap / HTML & CSS conversational

**UX:** User research / Usability testings / Qualitative interviews / User empathy / Competitors analysis / Heuristic Evaluation / Visual Prototyping & Wireframing / Storyboarding / A/B testings / Accessibility Testings / 5sec Testings

**UI:** Visual hierarchy / Layouts & grid systems / Typography / Color theory / Animation / **Other Skills:** Visual storytelling / Illustration & Character design / Branding / Photo editing

### **Relevant Experience**

## **Graphic Design Tutor Freelancer**

2018 – 2020 Athens, Greece

Introducing young professionals to digital tools such as Illustrator and After Effects, helping them understand the environment of these platforms, getting command of various techniques in order to develop their own personal projects and explore new possibilities.

## **Graphic / Digital Designer Medi Jeunesse**

2018 – 2020 Athens, Greece

- Part of a digital marketing team of 3 members, created content for digital campaigns (visual assets: static, gif, video for posts and fb ads) posted on a daily basis.
- Designed marketing collaterals and updated website content (slider ,article and offer banners) increasing the website engagement.
- Created visual assets for newsletter campaigns through mailchimp. All the above within a framework of upgrading the brand identity on a more coherent and corporate level.
- Stakeholders praised the initiative to create documents of concrete and accurate brand quidelines.
- The new customers acquired through digital channels increased from 10% to 45% of the total number of new customers.

Graphic / Digital Designer Redirect Digital Agency 2017– 2017 Athens, Greece

- Part of a creative team of 4 members (2 designers & 2 copywriters), designed social media posts for various brands following their guidelines
- Updated website visuals for various brands.
- Backing up with critical research and study the business proposal that won the team the contract of managing the social media for Netflix Greece.

### **Projects**

## We Care for Paws Foundation (WCPF) UX UI Group Project https://yiannispapadopoulos.github.io/casestudy/

Team's goal was to redesign the Foundation website in order to help visitors donate and search effectively for an animal to adopt, while reestablishing the site's sense of trust.

- Responsibilities: Structuring interview plan / Coordinating tests & iterations / High Fidelity
   Design & Style Guidelines / Copywriting / Presentation Content & Design
- **Skills & Technologies Used**: User Research (Interviews + Surveys) & Analysis, Persona Creation, User Experience Design (UI/UX), Interaction Design, Prototyping, In-Person User Testing, A/B Testing, Figma, Miro, InVision, Illustrator, Photoshop.

#### **Education**

# **UX/UI Design Bootcamp Certificate The George Washington University**

Feb 21 – Jul 21 Washington DC

An intensive 24-week long training in user-centric design research, design thinking, visual prototyping and wireframing, interface design, storyboarding, visual design theory, web prototyping with HTML5 and CSS, interaction design with JavaScript, jQuery and Bootstrap. Main skills learned consists of Figma, Miro, Invision and Bootstrap.

# MA in Communication Design Kingston University

Oct 12 – Aug 13 Kingston upon Thames, UK

Three 15-week modules, in an interdisciplinary Postgraduate framework, explored narrative, visual grammar, visual storytelling, interdisciplinary learning, personal development and conceptual thinking. Outcomes were based on visual research undertaken over a 15 week period and covered areas such as typography, layout design, advertising and space.

Main skills learned consists of Indesign, Screen Printing & experimenting on various design fields.